Finding Aid for Order of Pythian Sisters. Huron-Arbor Temple no. 66 (Ypsilanti, Mich.) records, 1903-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Order of Pythian Sisters. Huron-Arbor Temple no. 66 (Ypsilanti, Mich.) records 1903-1990
Order of Pythian Sisters. Huron-Arbor Temple no. 66 (Ypsilanti, Mich.).
2 linear feet and 1 oversize folder
8723 Bd 2; Bd Outsize
Women's affiliate of the Knights of Pythias. Minute books, annual reports, and other records of the Huron Temple (Ypsilanti, Mich.); also membership roster of the Arbor Temple (Ann Arbor, Mich.) which merged, ca. 1978, with the Huron Temple.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the organization, through Mrs. Virginia Davis (donor no. 7347 ) in July 1986. Additions were received in 2013.
The record group is open to research.
The Huron-Arbor Temple No. 66 of the Pythian Sisters is a merger of the Ypsilanti and Ann Arbor temples of the Pythian Sisters fraternal organization (the women's affiliate of the Knights of Pythias). The Ypsilanti temple was founded in 1903 as the Rathbone Sisters; the temple assumed the name Pythian Sisters in 1916.
The records include temple minutes, annual reports, minutes of the past chiefs club, and miscellaneous papers and reports. Also included is a membership roster of Temple 80 of Ann Arbor. The Ann Arbor Temple merged with Temple 66 in October 1979.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Knights of Pythias.; Women--Michigan--Ypsilanti--Societies and clubs.; Ypsilanti (Mich.); Order of Pythian Sisters. Arbor Temple no. 80 (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Order of Pythian Sisters. Huron Temple no. 66 (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Order of Pythian Sisters. Huron-Arbor Temple no. 66 (Ypsilanti, Mich.)
Contributors:
Order of Pythian Sisters. Huron Temple no. 66 (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Order of Pythian Sisters. Arbor Temple no. 80 (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
- Organizational Records
  (all Ypsilanti Temple unless otherwise indicated)
  - Minute books
    - Volume 1, 1908-1909 (Box 1)
    - Volume 2, 1910-May 1913 (Box 1)
    - Volume 3, June 1913-April 1916 (Box 1)
    - Volume 4, May 1916-May 1920 (Box 1)
    - Volume 5, June 1920-February 1923 (Box 1)
    - Volume 6, March 1923-March 1925 (Box 1)
    - Volume 7, Not received (Box 1)
    - Volume 8, January 1932-December 1937 (Box 1)
    - Volume 9, 1938-January 1942 (Box 1)
    - Volume 10, March 1942-February 1946 (Box 1)
    - Volume 11, October 1946-February 1951 (Box 1)
    - Volume 12, February 21, 1951-May 5, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Volume 13, May 5, 1954-December 1956 (Box 1)
    - Volume 14, 1957-April 6, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Volume 15, April 20, 1960-June 5, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Volume 16, June 19, 1963-December 1966 (Box 1)
    - Volume 17, 1967-April, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Volume 18, 1971-1976 (Box 2)
    - Volume 19, 1977-1980 (Box 2)
  - Roll of officers, 1903-1920 (Rathbone Sisters 1903-1915) (Box 2)
  - Membership lists, volume 1, 1903-ca. 1921 (Box 2)
  - Past Chiefs Club of Pythian Sisters
    - Minutes, May 1923-October 1928 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, November 1928-October 1938 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1939-January 1947 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, March 1947-December 1957 (Box 2)
    - Minutes (District 7 and 8), March 1941-April 1964 (Box 2)
  - Convention reports, ca. 1940-ca. 1968 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated, ca. 1936-ca. 1952 (Box 2)
  - History, 1903-1973 (Box 2)
  - Grand Temple of Michigan
    - Constitution (Box 2)
    - Officers' Reports
      - 1959-1960 (Box 2)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Membership roster, 1926-1990 (Folder Bd)
  - Annual reports
    - Volume 1, 1905-1920 (Folder Bd)
    - Volume 2, 1921-1938 (Folder Bd)
    - Volume 3, 1939-1968 (Folder Bd)
  - Membership roster (Arbor Temple No. 80), 1909-ca. 1958 (Folder Bd)